Cristhian Luna

Frontend Developer

Manta, Ecuador (GMT-5) (+593) 993 491 142 jobs.cluna@gmaill.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/devcluna https://devcluna.com

Frontend developer with 2+ years of experience developing web applications with React.js for SMEs in the region and the US. I have a high focus on responsive design, support for different browsers, SEO friendly, and remarkable execution performance. I am self-taught and communicative. I am currently looking for remote opportunities in the tech industry as a front-end developer with React.

Experience

Fulltime Force, Full Stack Developer — May 2022

Innovation (Peru) (Intern Project)

- Develop a candidates comparison module that helped the recruitment team to include the top 10% of the best candidates for the company.
- Improve by 60% user experience and reduce content redundancy by implementing UI changes.

Tech Stack: React.js, Redux, react-router, redux-toolkit, TypeScript, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind, Figma, Postman, JWT.

ViaFasken (EEUU) (customer)

- Reduced by 30% the number of vulnerabilities by collaborating in the implementation of a double authentication factor that improves the security of the application.
- Reduced by 50% the number of weekly tasks by providing support to the IT team in the deployment of new features in a short time.

Tech Stack: React.js, Redux, react-router, redux-toolkit, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind, Figma, Postman, JWT.

Gunderson (EUU) (customer)

- Reduced by 20% the number of bugs and reports by implementing unit testing and code refactoring.
- Increased interactions by 30% and reduced execution time by 60% by implementing UI changes and improvements in site navigation.

Tech Stack: React.js, Redux, react-router, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Figma, Postman. JWT.

ULEAM, Frontend Developer (Ecuador) — March 2021 - March 2022

- By creating an administrative panel where businesses could submit their job openings, I was able to quadruple the amount of job offers published each month.
- I built a module for applying for graduate students that allowed a 15% success rate in job applications.

Stack tecnológico: React.js, Redux, react-router, redux-thunk, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, HTML5, CSS3, Figma, MaterialUI.

BESE, Fullstack Developer (Ecuador) — May 2020 – September 2020

- Reduced by 30% the development time in the different teams by collaborating in the implementation of a Rest API infrastructure, enabling the data for the app.
- Increased the company's profits by 20% by providing relevant information at the Management level, with the implementation of a POS service and a front office.

Tech Stack: React.js, Redux, react-router, redux-thunk, TypeScript, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, HTML5, CSS3, Figma, JWT, MaterialUI.

Kans, Frontend Developer (Ecuador)— March 2019 - February 2020

- Reduced the duplication of roles by 100% through the development of a module for the administration of user accounts that allows setting roles, permissions, and responsibilities of the staff.
- Reduced by 20% development time by adding new views and components and including style libraries like Bootstrap and Font Awesome.

Tech Stack: React.js, Redux, react-router, redux-thunk, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, HTML5, CSS3, Electron.js, Bootstrap, Flrebase.

SKILLS

Program Languages: Advanced JavaScript, Basic: Python, Typescript

Frameworks & Libs: Advanced: React.js, HTML5, CSS3; Intermediate: ECMAscript v6, Redux, Toolkit, NodeJS, Express, Bcrypt, Styled-components, Tailwind, bootstrap Basic: Lodash, IEST, IWT, moment.js. mongoose, Formik.js

DataBases: Intermediate: MongoDB; Basic: PostgreSQL.

tools: Git, Slack, VS-code, Postman, NVM, Lighthouse (SEO), React--redux Dev tools, Flgma

Agile: Kanban

Languages: Fluid: English; Native: Spanish.

EDUCATION

Universidad Laica Eloy Alfaro de Manabi - *Manta, Ecuador. Science Degree, System Engineering, May 2022.*

CERTIFICATIONS

React – HackerRank. 2022.

JavaScript Algorithms & Data structures – freeCodeCamp. 2020.